guys we were just we're just talking
about gitlab and this cool cool tool
from ER Oden plots which is a a friend
of the stream on occasion they come by
here a good C coder amazing streamer and
uh all around you know great human being
and you know he made GLI to talk to
GitHub and G laab and everything and I I
just want to make a quick video about
why I I made lots of videos about this
in the past but I just want to reiterate
my hatred for G lab has coming from
three reasons
the first one is gitlab is ridiculously
slow the API is the it's it I mean
whatever is causing it it's really
really slow the UI is slow the UI is
prettier but it's totally slow and it
also has gatekeeping blocking so you
can't browse repost unless you have a
gitlab account and all kinds of weird
things that just kind of get in your way
um and that's the number one reason the
number two reason it's written in Ruby
right the number two reason by the way
if you try to install gitlab server uh
uh good luck no way it is a pain in the
butt to set up and it's so slow it's
just so bad number two and I love gitlab
this is what sucked I was pushing for
everybody to go to gitlab because it
would win number two and this is the
other main reason this is the pain point
that reminded me of this I was on gitlab
and I was making code I was writing my
own code to talk to the API the G the
gitlab API is ridiculously stupid it's
so bad and apparently the author of this
tool has complained about the same thing
now you know the G the GI Hub API uses
grab ql pretty overzealously I think
it's kind of over engineered by tell you
what it's amazing it's amazing it it
does things that are intuitive it's
really great and it's super easy to code
against um and three the main this is
the nail and the copin GitHub made their
own commandline API tool that that
directly talks to some of the backend
and get up his Ruby some of it is but
the statement that GitHub is Ruby is a
lie it's mostly Elixir actually if last
time I checked somebody correct me in
the comments if I'm wrong on that if you
know exactly what's going on there um
there is some Ruby jles in there and
stuff so but the third thing is I mean
whether whether or not it's it doesn't
matter GitHub is not slow you can say a
lot of things about GitHub the things
you can't say about GitHub is that it is
slow the website is not slow the API is
not slow I have never ever had a
complaint about slowness so in terms of
integration the GitHub command line tool
is way way better than anything out
there in the world right now so if if
you and and obviously the fourth reason
which is a major reason for everybody
it's usually their first reason is
GitHub is in the time that I did the
evaluation I made another video about
this but in the time that I did my
evaluation of Gab versus GitHub GitHub
added something like 8 million users and
gitlab didn't and which brings me I
guess there sort of a a reason I hadn't
thought of and that is gitlab is built
entirely almost a largest a huge
percentage of gitlab Depends entirely on
open source contributions which on the
surface seems like a really great thing
but it's really not because as much as
you hate Microsoft that you know and all
their their you know stealing a private
data and GitHub and all that and putting
it into their Ai and all those things
that Microsoft does as much as you might
hate him for that GitHub dominates it's
got the greatest to option it's got
you're most more likely to get a job
from having a get up account than
anything else and it doesn't depend on
open source contributions it does take
open source contributions but it doesn't
depend on them so I you can complain
about GitHub all you want and I'm going
to get ha in the comments I don't care
if you're watching this because you want
to be taken seriously use GitHub sorry